

Alexander Potapov

Moscow, Russia +7 (985) 389-24-21 alexander.potapov.w@yandex.ru

in linkedin | github

telegram | 🖪 habr | 💷 blog

SUMMARY

C++/Vulkan graphics developer. Working on rendering engine backend, shader compilers and game engine internals. Have experience with OpenGL, DirectX11 and Vulkan API. Proficient in working with large code bases, optimizing and debugging rendering code (RenderDoc, NSight). Interested in real-time rendering, low-level programming and game engine design.

EDUCATION _

HIGHER SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS UNIVERSITY

2020-Now / Moscow, Russia

B.S IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

• Calculus, Linear Algebra, Discrete Mathematics, Software Development, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture

EXPERIENCE

NANOSEMANTICS 2020-2021 / Moscow, Russia

C++/PYTHON SOFTWARE ENGINEER

• working on programming language design, compiler design, python/C++ interop

EAGLE DYNAMICS 2021-Now / Moscow, Russia

3D GRAPHICS DEVELOPER

• working on Vulkan rendering backend, game engine internals, shader cross-compilers

SKILLS ___

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES *Experienced:* C++ *Familiar:* C# | Python

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT Object Oriented Programming | GIT | CMake | GitLab | CI

GRAPHICS PROGRAMMING Deferred Rendering | Physically-Based Rendering | Render Graph | RenderDoc

LIBRARIES OpenGL | DirectX11 | Vulkan | GLSL/HLSL | DXVK | GNU Bison/ANTLR

LANGUAGES Native: Russian Fluent: English

OPEN-SOURCE PROJECTS

MxEngine	General-purpose 3D game engine (deferred rendering, PBR, physics, audio, editor tools)	github
VAL	Render Graph-based Vulkan rendering library (automatic barriers, shader reflection)	github
FLUID SIMULATION	2D realtime fluid simulation from GPUGems book (with CUDA as compute backed)	github
PATH TRACER	GLSL path tracer (based on MxEngine, supports diffuse, reflective and transparent objects)	github
MSL	Dynamic-typed programming language (Bison parser, bytecode compiler, custom VM)	github
ANGOURIMATH	Symbolic algebra library for C# (one of main contributors, worked on analytic solvers)	github

EXTRA

FAVOURITE BOOKS

- Game Engine Architecture by Jason Gregory
- Effective Modern C++ by Scott Meyers
- Modern C++ Design by Andrei Alexandrescu

FAVOURITE TALKS

- Marvel's Spider-Man: A Technical Postmortem (GDC)
- Mike Acton "Data-Oriented Design and C++" (CppCon)
- Evolving Path of Exile's Renderer (ExileCon)

FAVOURITE GAMES

- Witcher 3
- Dark Souls III
- Doom Eternal